

#### **ENGINEER** · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

12, Quai Paul Wiltzer - 57000 Metz, Grand Est, France

■ +33(0)6 3780 5997 | ✓ mkreutner@gmail.com | 👑 December 5th, 1975 | 🔠 www.mkdevs.eu | 🖸 mkreutner | 🔟 mkreutner | 🛗 michel-kreutner-2a953834 | 🗶 @michel\_kreutner | 🚾 mkreutner

Be the change that you want to see in the world.

### About me ... \_\_\_

I have many years of experience in the field of information technology combined with a solid background in the field of automation, computer signal processing as well as a strong ability to acquire new knowledge and skills. I can work both in a team and independently. I have a strong sense of organization and proven skills in system administration, development (WEB, API), DevOps and editorial.

## Skills\_\_\_\_\_

**DevOps** AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Kubernetes,

Rancher, Vagrant, Packer, Terraform, Jenkins, CI/CD, GitHub, GitLab

**Programming** Python, PHP, C#, ASP, C/C++, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, LESS, SASS, LaTeX **Frameworks / Libraries** Flask, Django, FastAPI, Symfony, Laravel, .Net, React, Angular, Bootstrap, TailWind

LanguagesFrench (Mother tongue), English (B1 - Intermediate)MethodsScrum, Kandan, Waterfall, XP, Pair programming

**Others** Open-minded, Persevering, Listening, Proactive, Team Player, Organized

# **Experience**

#### AxioCode - Web and Mobile development

Developer

02/2024 - Present

Metz, France - On-Site

#### Context

Within one of the business/client teams, I am responsible for implementing new features for different applications and more specifically:

- Development and Maintenance of the Core application that centralizes business information, provides a BackOffice and an API for different business applications (C#.Net, ASP.Net and Framework .Net 4.5/4.6);
- Development of the new Core application (C#, .Net Core);
- Technical referent for the implementation of applications in lightweight containers (Docker, k8s);
- Implementation of docker stacks for development, integration and production environments;
- Implementation of CI/CD workflows;

Technical referent for the implementation of a centralized management solution for users and their access rights to applications. As well as the implementation of an SSO.

#### **Technical environment**

- C#, .Net Framework 4.5/4.6, .NetCore, Gitlab, Gitlab-CI, Docker, k8s;
- PostgreSQL, MariaDB, SQL Server 2019

#### **GVA Africa - FTTH Deployment in Central Africa**

Paris, France - Full Remote

08/2023 - 02/2024

# IT DEVELOPER Context

Within the development SI team, I am in lead to correct and implement news features on several applications. I'm in charge of:

- Maintaining technical documentation of API;
- Develop new features and correct bugs on APIs for network management;
- Develop new features and correct bugs on administration tools;
- Technical referent for New ONT call for tenders;

#### **Technical environment**

- Python 3.7+, Django 4.x and Django Rest Framework, Flask, Peewee, Ansible, Gitlab, Gitlab-CI;
- OLT, ONT, Debian Server, Network Equipment;
- PostgreSQL;

**Education** 

IAEM Doctoral School Nancy, France

PhD. (Philosopiae Doctor) - Automatic and Robotics

09/2000 - 09/2004

· Subject: Multisensory perception for the positioning of an autonomous vehicle dedicated for disabled people.

INP Lorraine Nancy, Lorraine

MASTER OF SCIENCE (NVQ LEVEL 5) - AUTOMATIC AND ROBOTICS

09/1998 - 09/1999

- Mastering the different technologies related to automatic and robotics;
- Design, develop and optimize an application including automatic and robotics;
- · Lead a project independently by integrating budget management, supplier or subcontractor management;
- Manage the department's activities;
- · Communicate and exchange in technical English.

University of Lorraine Metz, France

BACHELOR'S DEGREE OF SCIENCE (BSC DEGREE) AND MASTER'S DEGREE OF SCIENCE (MSC DEGREE) IN INDUSTRIAL SYSTEMS

09/1996 - 09/1998

**ENGINEERING WITH COMPUTER SCIENCE OPTION** 

- · Train engineer-level executives' competences for operations management, industrial system, production and logistics delivery;
- with a strong openness to the challenges of operating a company;
- with transversal skills such as listening skills, interpersonal skills, negotiation and communication skills, mastery of at least one foreign language.

**Louis Vincent High School** 

Metz France

BTEC HIGHER NATIONAL DIPLOMA IN INDUSTRIAL CONTROL AND AUTOMATIC REGULATION

09/1994 - 09/1996

The holder of the Advanced Technician Certificate in Industrial Control and Automation has all the necessary skills to resolve malfunctions related to the automation of equipment and major continuous industrial manufacturing processes whose production cycle cannot be stopped. He masters the command, control and regulation phases.

# **Extracurricular Activity**

#### B10S (B1t 0n the Security, Underground hacker team)

S.Korea

CORE MEMBER

Nov. 2011 - PRESENT

- Gained expertise in penetration testing areas, especially targeted on web application and software.
- Participated on a lot of hacking competition and won a good award.
- Held several hacking competitions non-profit, just for fun.

#### WiseGuys (Hacking & Security research group)

S Korea

 $\mathsf{Member}$ 

Jun. 2012 - PRESENT

- Gained expertise in hardware hacking areas from penetration testing on several devices including wireless router, smartphone, CCTV and settop box.
- Trained wannabe hacker about hacking technique from basic to advanced and ethics for white hackers by hosting annual Hacking Camp.

#### PoApper (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

CORE MEMBER & PRESIDENT AT 2013

Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2017

- · Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.
- Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

#### PLUS (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MEMBER

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.

#### MSSA (Management Strategy Club of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017

MEMBER

- Gained knowledge about several business field like Management, Strategy, Financial and marketing from group study.
- · Gained expertise in business strategy areas and inisght for various industry from weekly industry analysis session.

## **Honors & Awards**

NATIONAL AWARDS

2005 **1rst**, National Academy of Metz Scientific Distinction

Metz, France

# **Certificates**

2023 Awa Certified Developer - Associate, Amazon web services (Awa)	
2023 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2022 <b>AWS Certified Security - Specialty</b> , Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2022 <b>AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Professional</b> , Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2019 <b>AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate</b> , Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2021 <b>AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate</b> , Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2020 <b>Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD),</b> The Linux Foundation	
2023 HashiCorp Certified: Consul Associate (002), HashiCorp	
2023 HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003), HashiCorp	
2020 HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (002), HashiCorp	
Presentation	
DevFest Seoul by Google Developer Group Korea	Seoul, S.Korea
Presenter for <hosting and="" application="" cloudflare="" for="" free="" github,="" netlify="" utilizing="" web=""></hosting>	Nov. 2017
<ul> <li>Introduced the history of web technology and the JAM stack which is for the modern web applicat</li> <li>Introduced how to freely host the web application with high performance utilizing global CDN serve</li> </ul>	
6th CodeEngn (Reverse Engineering Conference)	Seoul, S.Korea
Presenter for <defcon 20th:="" go="" las="" the="" to="" vegas="" way=""></defcon>	Jul. 2012
• Introduced CTF(Capture the Flag) hacking competition and advanced techniques and strategy for	CTF
6th Hacking Camp - S.Korea	S.Korea
Presenter for <metasploit 101=""></metasploit>	Sep. 2012
Introduced basic procedure for penetration testing and how to use Metasploit	
Smart wheelchair perception using odometry, ultrasound sensors and camera  Speaker Writer	Publication Robotica, vol. 27, num. 2, pp. 303-310 2009
	Publication Robotica, vol. 27, num.
Smart wheelchair perception using odometry, ultrasound sensors and camera	2, pp. 303-310
Speaker& Writer	07/2006
Smart wheelchair perception using odometry, ultrasound sensors and camera	Publication Robotica, vol. 27, num.
onare meeting perception and governors), actions and control and control	2, pp. 303-310
Speaker& Writer	2009
Smart wheelchair perception using odometry, ultrasound sensors and camera	Publication Robotica, vol. 27, num.
Speaker& Writer	2, pp. 303-310 2009
	Publication Robotica, vol. 27, num.
Smart wheelchair perception using odometry, ultrasound sensors and camera	2, pp. 303-310
Speaker& Writer	2009
Program Committees	
2016 <b>Problem Writer</b> , 2016 CODEGATE Hacking Competition World Final	S.Korea
2013 <b>Organizer &amp; Co-director</b> , 1st POSTECH Hackathon	S.Korea
2012 <b>Staff</b> , 7th Hacking Camp	S.Korea
2012 <b>Problem Writer</b> , 1st Hoseo University Teenager Hacking Competition	S.Korea

AWS Certified Advanced Networking - Specialty, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

**AWS Certified Developer - Associate**, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

2023

2023

2012

S.Korea

**Staff & Problem Writer**, JFF(Just for Fun) Hacking Competition